{
    "id": "3298849477bc47b4a7fe9783494a69f8",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Sam ................................... his homework for two years.",
            "description": "The present perfect continuous tense is used to talk about actions or situations that started in the past and has continued up to the present.",
            "answers": [
                "was doing",
                "is doing",
                "has been doing"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "We ................................ a strange experience yesterday.",
            "description": "The simple past is used to say when something happened in the past.",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "had",
                "had had"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He .................................... for Singapore last week.",
            "description": "The simple past is used to say when something happened in the past.",
            "answers": [
                "left",
                "had left",
                "has left"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "See that you ................................... disturb the patients.",
            "description": "The simple present is used in imperative structures.",
            "answers": [
                "do not",
                "did not",
                "is not"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "You will win if you .................................. hard.",
            "description": "In the first conditional we use the simple present tense in the if-clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause.structures.",
            "answers": [
                "work",
                "worked",
                "have worked"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The post mortem report proved that the man ........................................ ten hours ago.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "has been killed",
                "had been killed",
                "was killed"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The train .................................. by the time we reached the station.",
            "description": "We use the past perfect for the earlier of two past actions. ",
            "answers": [
                "left",
                "has left",
                "had left"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Every morning, I .................................. for 30 minutes.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about habitual actions in the present.",
            "answers": [
                "meditated",
                "am meditating",
                "meditate"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He .................................... school at fifteen.",
            "description": "The simple past is used to talk about finished past events. ",
            "answers": [
                "left",
                "has left",
                "had left"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "You cannot meet him now. He ................................ home.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to talk about finished events whose effect is still felt in the present.",
            "answers": [
                "went",
                "has gone",
                "went"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "When we visited her she ................................. bed ridden for six months.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "has been",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ……………………………… to me, you wouldn’t land in trouble.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "listen",
                "listened",
                "have listened"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}